A Guide to the Lucille P. Markey Charitable Trust records FA017
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Governance, 1981-1998; 3
  - Chairman, Board of Trustees, 1954-1997 1982-1997; 2
    - General Correspondence, 1983 (Reel 137, Frame 730)
    - General Correspondence, 1984 (Reel 138, Frame 1)
    - General Correspondence, 1985 (Reel 138, Frame 354)
    - General Correspondence, 1986 (Reel 138, Frame 696)
    - General Correspondence, 1987 (Reel 139, Frame 1)
    - General Correspondence, 1988 (Reel 139, Frame 171)
    - General Correspondence, 1989 (Reel 139, Frame 492)
    - General Correspondence, 1990 (Reel 139, Frame 759)
    - General Correspondence, 1991 (Reel 140, Frame 1)
    - General Correspondence, 1992 (Reel 140, Frame 124)
    - General Correspondence, 1993 (Reel 140, Frame 292)
    - General Correspondence, 1994 (Reel 140, Frame 447)
    - General Correspondence, 1995 (Reel 140, Frame 564)
    - General Correspondence, 1996 (Reel 140, Frame 730)
    - General Correspondence, 1997 (Reel 140, Frame 921)
    - Glaser, Robert J. - Correspondence, 1983 (Reel 141, Frame 1)
    - Glaser, Robert J. - Correspondence, 1984 (Reel 141, Frame 121)
    - Glaser, Robert J. - Correspondence, 1985-1987 (Reel 141, Frame 335)
    - Glaser, Robert J. - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Reel 141, Frame 618)
    - Glaser, Robert J. - Correspondence, 1990-1993 (Reel 142, Frame 1)
    - Glaser, Robert J. - Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Reel 142, Frame 151)
    - Glass, Margaret B. - Correspondence, 1982-1986 (Reel 142, Frame 396)
    - Glass, Margaret B. - Correspondence, 1987-1996 (Reel 142, Frame 638)
    - Heraty, Laurette - Correspondence, 1954-1989, bulk 1983-1989; bulk (Reel 143, Frame 1)
    - MacArthur Foundation, 1984-1985 (Reel 143, Frame 163)
    - Projects - Ginzberg Report - The Financing of Biomedical Research: The Potential for Philanthropy (Reel 143, Frame 209)
    - Projects - Herman Project - The Clinical Researcher (Reel 143, Frame 238)
    - Projects - The Physician-Scientist: Background (Reel 143, Frame 316)
    - Projects - The Physician-Scientist (Reel 143, Frame 569)
    - Projects - Rockefeller Archive Center (Reel 143, Frame 683)
    - Projects - Rockefeller University (Reel 143, Frame 751)
    - Shinn, George - Correspondence, 1984-1996 (Reel 143, Frame 841)
    - Sutter, William P. - Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Reel 144, Frame 1)
    - Sutter, William P. - Correspondence, 1985-1992 (Reel 144, Frame 181)
    - Sutter, William P. - Correspondence, 1993-1997 (Reel 144, Frame 371)
    - Trust History - Authors and Arrangements, 1984-1994 (Reel 144, Frame 438)
    - Trust History - Chronology, 1984-1992 (Reel 144, Frame 481)
    - Trust History - General, 1987-1994, bulk 1992-1994; bulk (Reel 144, Frame 569)
    - Trust History - General Organizational Charts, 1989-1995 (Reel 144, Frame 706)
    - Trust History - Hector, Louis J., 1991-1997 (Reel 144, Frame 766)
    - Trust History - Judson, Horace, 1993-1997 (Reel 145, Frame 1)
    - Trust History - Lagemann, Ellen Condliffe, 1993-1996 (Reel 145, Frame 281)
    - Trustees Meeting Notes, 1984-1993 (Reel 145, Frame 305)
    - Trustees Memoranda, 1983-1985 (Reel 145, Frame 401)
    - Trustees Memoranda, 1986-1990 (Reel 145, Frame 657)
    - Trustees Memoranda, 1991-1996 (Reel 146, Frame 1)
    - Trustees' and Officers' Biographies (Reel 146, Frame 261)
  - Director for Medical Science, 1981-1997; 3
    The files of the Director for Medical Science, Dr. Robert J. Glaser, refer to meeting think tanks held during 1984-1985, program development and evaluations, and the formation of a Robert J. Glaser Commemorative.
    - Axion Research Foundation (Reel 146, Frame 347)
    - Center for Community Health Education, Research and Service (Reel 146, Frame 350)
    - Knowlton Scholar Fund (Reel 146, Frame 365)
    - Liberal Arts Colleges - Science Education and Research (Reel 146, Frame 370)
    - Mt. Zion Hospital and Medical Center (Reel 146, Frame 381)
    - Research Articles and Papers (Reel 146, Frame 396)
    - Shriver Center for Mental Retardation, Inc. (Reel 146, Frame 493)
    - Totts Gap (Reel 146, Frame 498)
    - Whittier Institute (Reel 146, Frame 520)
  - Annual Reports, 1983-1996; 4
    This subseries is arranged chronologically.
    Individual annual reports, biennial reports, and other term reports are included in this subseries and represent the full fifteen year limited term of the Trust's operation.
    - Five-Year Report, 1983-1988 (Reel 146, Frame 528)
    - Annual Report, 1989 (Reel 146, Frame 577)
    - Annual Report, 1990 (Reel 146, Frame 594)
    - Annual Report, 1991 (Reel 146, Frame 612)
    - Annual Report, 1992 (Reel 146, Frame 630)
    - Annual Report, 1993 (Reel 146, Frame 651)
    - Annual Report, 1994 (Reel 146, Frame 672)
    - Annual Report, 1995 (Reel 146, Frame 695)
    - Final Report, 1983-1996 (Reel 146, Frame 720)
- Program Development, 1982-1996; 4
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  This series includes the records of the Director for Program Administration, Nancy W. Weber. The material in this series discusses overall program planning and grants administration. Information pertaining to the formation of award categories, think tank meetings, publicity and press releases, overhead policy, and grant planning are detailed.
  - Early Trust Correspondence, 1982-1991, bulk 1982-1991; bulk (Reel 146, Frame 762)
  - General Organizational Correspondence, 1991-1996, bulk 1991-1992; bulk (Reel 146, Frame 852)
  - General Organizational Review, 1991-1992 (Reel 147, Frame 1)
  - Grant Planning, 1985-1996 (Reel 147, Frame 200)
  - International Network, 1985-1987 (Reel 147, Frame 428)
  - Meetings - Howard Hughes Medical Institute Research Conference, January 26, 1982 (Reel 147, Frame 462)
  - Meetings - Markey West, April 24, 1984 (Reel 147, Frame 508)
  - Meetings - Markey East, May 10, 1984 (Reel 147, Frame 591)
  - Meetings - Think Tank - London, England, September 6, 1984 (Reel 147, Frame 702)
  - Meetings - Markey West II, March 13, 1985 (Reel 147, Frame 775)
  - Meetings - Think Tank, February 7, 1985 (Reel 147, Frame 799)
  - News Releases, 1983-1987 (Reel 148, Frame 1)
  - Overhead Policy, 1985-1987 (Reel 148, Frame 188)
  - Physician-Scientiest Training and Development, 1989-1990 (Reel 148, Frame 228)
  - Predoctoral Annual Reports, 1983-1987 (Reel 148, Frame 296)
  - Predoctoral - General, 1984-1989 (Reel 148, Frame 331)
  - Program Announcement Letters, 1984 (Reel 148, Frame 378)
  - Program Development, 1984 (Reel 148, Frame 692)
  - Program Evaluation, 1991-1996 (Reel 148, Frame 845)
  - Program Information and Guidelines - Draft Versions, 1987-1991 (Reel 148, Frame 889)
  - Research at Liberal Arts Colleges, 1985-1988 (Reel 149, Frame 1)
  - Research Articles and Papers, 1983-1987 (Reel 149, Frame 54)
  - Robert J. Glaser Commemorative Proposal, 1991-1992 (Reel 149, Frame 94)
  - Visiting Lecturers, 1984-1989 (Reel 149, Frame 144)
- Correspondence, 1962-1997, bulk 1981-1997; bulk; 5
  Series 5 is arranged in three subseries:
  Subseries 1 - Foundation Correspondence
  Subseries 2 - Grants Administration General Correspondence
  Subseries 3 - Trustees' Correspondence
  Separate correspondence files were maintained by the program administration.
  - Foundation Correspondence, 1962-1997, bulk 1981-1997; bulk; 1
    - Association for Animals and Animal Research, 1988 (Reel 149, Frame 291)
    - Arthritis Foundation, 1985-1986 (Reel 149, Frame 321)
    - Blue Grass Boy's Ranch, 1962-1995, bulk 1983-1987; bulk (Reel 149, Frame 341)
    - British Schools and Universities Foundation, Inc., 1984 (Reel 149, Frame 534)
    - Burroughs Wellcome Fund, 1987-1994 (Reel 149, Frame 537)
    - Chicago Community Trust - Searle Scholars Program, 1983-1986 (Reel 149, Frame 603)
    - Jane Coffin Childs Memorial Fund for Medical Research, 1988 (Reel 149, Frame 664)
    - Council on Foundations, 1982-1990 (Reel 149, Frame 674)
    - Donors Forum of Miami, 1989-1997 (Reel 149, Frame 739)
    - Foundation Center, 1984-1996 (Reel 150, Frame 1)
    - Foundations - Miscellaneous, 1984-1997 (Reel 150, Frame 152)
    - Grantmakers in Health, 1983-1992 (Reel 150, Frame 227)
    - Howard Hughes Medical Institute, 1978-1996 (Reel 150, Frame 295)
    - Institute for the Advancement of Health, 1983 (Reel 150, Frame 644)
    - Iowa Methodist Health Foundation, 1994 (Reel 150, Frame 654)
    - James S. McDonnell Foundation, 1986 (Reel 150, Frame 656)
    - John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation, 1984-1990 (Reel 150, Frame 668)
    - McKnight Foundation, 1984-1985 (Reel 150, Frame 684)
    - Maurice Falk Medical Fund, 1983, 1993 (Reel 150, Frame 700)
    - Mayo Foundation, 1983-1984 (Reel 150, Frame 714)
    - Medical Foundation, Inc., 1981-1984 (Reel 150, Frame 719)
    - National Kidney Foundation, 1993 (Reel 150, Frame 733)
    - National Multiple Sclerosis Society, 1986 (Reel 150, Frame 737)
    - National Neurofibromatosis Foundation, Inc., 1986-1987 (Reel 150, Frame 746)
    - National Science Foundation, 1989 (Reel 150, Frame 755)
    - National Society to Prevent Blindness - Florida Affiliate, 1986 (Reel 150, Frame 757)
    - Pew Charitable Trusts, 1985-1996 (Reel 150, Frame 806)
    - Picker Foundation, 1985 (Reel 150, Frame 879)
    - Rand Corporation, 1986 (Reel 150, Frame 885)
    - Research Corporation, 1984 (Reel 150, Frame 899)
    - Robert Johnson Wood Foundation, 1990, 1992 (Reel 150, Frame 904)
    - Tinker Foundation, Inc., 1985 (Reel 150, Frame 908)
    - Venture Technology Association, 1984 (Reel 150, Frame 916)
    - Whitaker Foundation, 1987 (Reel 150, Frame 930)
  - Grants Administration General Correspondence, 1983-1997; 2
    - General Correspondence, 1983 (Reel 151, Frame 1)
    - General Correspondence, 1984 (Reel 151, Frame 13)
    - General Correspondence, 1985 (Reel 151, Frame 184)
    - General Correspondence, 1986 (Reel 151, Frame 474)
    - General Correspondence, 1987 (Reel 151, Frame 634)
    - General Correspondence, 1988 (Reel 151, Frame 693)
    - General Correspondence, 1989 (Reel 152, Frame 1)
    - General Correspondence, 1990 (Reel 152, Frame 144)
    - General Correspondence, 1991 (Reel 152, Frame 239)
    - General Correspondence, 1992 (Reel 152, Frame 366)
    - General Correspondence, 1993 (Reel 152, Frame 405)
    - General Correspondence, 1994 (Reel 152, Frame 449)
    - General Correspondence, 1995 (Reel 152, Frame 483)
    - General Correspondence, 1996 (Reel 152, Frame 506)
    - General Correspondence, 1997 (Reel 152, Frame 509)
  - Trustees' Correspondence, 1981-1997; 3
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondent's last name.
    - Glaser, Robert J. - Correspondence, 1983-1992 (Reel 152, Frame 511)
    - Glass, Margaret B. - Correspondence, 1984-1997 (Reel 152, Frame 852)
    - Hector, Louis J. - Correspondence, 1981-1995 (Reel 152, Frame 947)
    - Heraty, Laurette - Correspondence, 1983-1989 (Reel 152, Frame 1025)
    - Sutter, William P. - Correspondence, 1982-1997 (Reel 153, Frame 1)
- Scrapbook, Photographs and Miscellany, 1931-1997, bulk 1982-1997; bulk; 6
  This series is arranged in three subseries:
  Subseries 1 - Scrapbook
  Subseries 2 - Photographs
  Subseries 3 - Miscellany
  - Scrapbook, 1984-1996; 1
    The scrapbook includes newspaper clippings, press releases, and mostly published milestone information about the Markey Trust.
    - Scrapbook, 1984-1996 (Reel 154, Frame 1)
  - Photographs, 1951-1996; 2
    Arrangement
    The photographs that comprise this subseries have been moved from their original locations within the collection.
    The photographs include formal and informal group portraits of scholars' annual events and commemorations, Board of Trustees, the Trustees Committee, the Selection Committee, and the administrative headquarter offices in Miami, Florida.
    Photographs of Lucille and Admiral Markey and views of Calumet Farms and race track events attended by the Markeys at Kentucky and Florida tracks are also included in this subseries.
    - Photographs from Series 1, Subseries 3 (Reel 154, Frame 2)
    - Photographs from Series 1, Subseries 4, Section B (Reel 154, Frame 3)
    - Photographs from Series 2 (Reel 154, Frame 4)
    - Photographs from Series 3, Subseries 1, Section D (Reel 154, Frame 5)
    - Photographs from Series 1, Subseries 4, Section B (Reel 155, Frame 1)
    - Photographs from Series 3, Subseries 1, Section D (Reel 155, Frame 2)
    - Photographs from Series 3, Subseries 2 (Reel 155, Frame 3)
    - Photographs from Series 6, Subseries 3 (Reel 155, Frame 4)
  - Miscellany, 1931-1997; 3
    Information pertaining to Calumet Farm and the auction of its contents in 1992 are found in this subseries. The Auction Booklet includes photographs of trophies, interiors of the house, stables, equipment and a variety of possessions. For more information about Calumet Farm, please consult:
    Auerback, Ann Hagedorn. "Wild Ride: The Rise and Fall of Calumet Farm, Inc., America's Premier Racing Dynasty." New York: Henry Holt & Company, 1994.
    - Calumet Farm - Newspaper Articles, 1931-1997 (Reel 155, Frame 5)
    - Calumet Farm Auction Guide, March 26, 1992 (Reel 155, Frame 6)